John O'Neill

Work History

WEB DEVELOPER

The Murray State News | June 2019 - May 2022

- -Responsible for all website development and web content creation/editing on www.thenews.org
- -Assisted with social media content creation and posts on all social accounts

(Facebook audience over 12,000)

PRESIDENT OF SOCIAL MEDIA/VIDEO DESIGN Murray State University Racer Band | July 2020 - July 2022

- -Ensured all posts on Instagram and Facebook were created and posted at the requested scheduled times.
- -Worked closely with a team of photographers and videographers to design all content recorded for posts.

BRAND PARTNERSHIPS COORDINATOR BYGmusic | May 2021 - August 2021

- -Interned as an active member of the marketing team by completing multiple client lead generation lists and organization charts for the head of the department to use for proposals that leverage online engagement rates.
- -Worked with the Head of Brand Partnerships to create unique sponsorship events for musicians at Three Points Music Festival in Miami, and Arc Music Festival in Chicago in order to generate online engagement for Rip It Energy Drinks.

WEB DEVELOPER

Whitehardt | August 2022 - January 2024

Responsible for creating/managing client websites and developing new content and web elements using Wordpress, Advanced Custom Fields, HTML, PHP, CSS, and Javascript.

Education History

MURRAY STATE UNIVERSITY 2017 - 2022

Bachelor's of Science (BS), Business Administration & Music Business

- -Performed as a drummer for the Murray State Racer Band, Symphonic Band, Orchestra, and Jazz Band each semester.
- -Gained valuable knowledge of business operations by taking Financial Accounting, Managerial Accounting, Business Plan Development, and Marketing courses..

LEXINGTON HIGHSCHOOL 2013 - 2017

Contact Details

Email:

-oneilljohn22@gmail.com

Cell:

731-798-6104

Personal Profile

Hey there! I am a Nashville web developer and designer with 4+ years of experience. I am fluent in all stages of website discovery, design, development, QA, and launch processes and I have a passion for making websites look and run great.

Professional Skills

- -HTMI
- -CSS
- -PHP
- -Git
- -JavaScript
- -Node.js
- -TypeScript
- -Wordpress
- -Advanced Custom Fields
- -Social Media Strategy Creation/Execution
- -Digital Profile Optimization Auditing
- -Webpage /Social Media Content Design
- -Trained in Adobe Premier Pro, AfterEffects, and InDesign

-Page Speed Debugging

- -Graphic Design
- -Social Media Analytics Reporting
- -Online Trend Identification/Implementation

Traits

- -Organized and detailed oriented worker
- -Thrives in collaborative environments
- -Used to dealing with stress and deadlines
- -Welcoming of constructive criticism
- -Easy to teach
- -Adaptable